<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>


<ScrollView android:layout_width="match_parent"
    android:layout_height="match_parent"
    android:layout_centerHorizontal="true"
    android:layout_alignParentTop="true"
    xmlns:android="http://schemas.android.com/apk/res/android">

    <RelativeLayout xmlns:android="http://schemas.android.com/apk/res/android"
        xmlns:tools="http://schemas.android.com/tools"
        android:id="@+id/activity_utifo"
        android:layout_width="match_parent"
        android:layout_height="wrap_content"
        android:paddingBottom="@dimen/activity_vertical_margin"
        android:paddingLeft="@dimen/activity_horizontal_margin"
        android:paddingRight="@dimen/activity_horizontal_margin"
        android:paddingTop="@dimen/activity_vertical_margin"
        tools:context="com.example.elwis.ucarereadytohelp.Utifo">


        <TextView
            android:text="










                                                                                                     Urinary tract infections (UTIs) are a common type of infection caused by bacteria (most often E. coli) that travel up the urethra to the bladder. A bladder infection is called cystitis. If bacterial infection spreads to the kidneys and ureters, the condition is called pyelonephritis. Urinary tract infections (UTIs) can be divided into upper tract infections, which involve the kidneys (pyelonephritis), and lower tract infections, which involve the bladder (cystitis), urethra (urethritis), and prostate (prostatitis). However, in practice, and particularly in children, differentiating between the sites may be difficult or impossible. The optimal regimen for investigating children with urinary tract infection (UTI) remains uncertain. Ultrasonography, contrast micturating cystourethrography (MCU), intravenous urography (IVU), and technetium-99m dimercaptosuccinic acid (DMSA) studies were performed in 58 children with UTI under 14 years of age attending two teaching hospitals and the results compared. All four investigations were normal in 12 children. In 36 with vesicoureteric reflux (VUR) on MCU, dilatation was reported on ultrasonography in eight children. Radiological renal scarring was seen in 20 children; it was suspected on ultrasonography in nine, with dilatation alone in four, and a normal report in seven. Duplex kidneys identified on IVU were unrecognised on ultrasonography or DMSA studies; ultrasonography showed no change corresponding to presume acute defects on DMSA studies that later resolved. Disparities were observed at all ages. Moreover, infection often spreads from one area to the other. Although urethritis and prostatitis are infections that involve the urinary tract, the term UTI usually refers to pyelonephritis and cystitis. Most cystitis and pyelonephritis are caused by bacteria. The most common nonbacterial pathogens are fungi (usually candidal species), and, less commonly, mycobacteria, viruses, and parasites. Nonbacterial pathogens usually affect patients who are immunocompromised, have diabetes, obstruction, or structural urinary tract abnormalities; or have had recent urinary tract instrumentation. Other than adenoviruses (implicated in haemorrhagic cystitis), viruses have no major contribution to UTI in immunocompetent patients. The predominant parasitic causes of UTIs are filariasis, trichomoniasis, leishmaniasis, malaria, and schistosomiasis. Of the parasitic diseases, only trichomoniasis is common in the US, usually as a sexually transmitted disease (STD). Urethritis is usually caused by an STD. Prostatitis is usually caused by a bacterium and is sometimes caused by an STD. Women are more susceptible to urinary tract infections than men, and their infections tend to recur. One reason is that the urethra (the tube that carries urine away from the bladder) is shorter in women than in men. Pregnancy does not increase the risk of getting a urinary tract infection but it can increase the risk of developing a serious infection that could potentially harm the mother and fetus. Pregnant women should report any symptoms of UTIs to their doctors, and should get screened for asymptomatic bacteriuria (presence of significant numbers of bacteria without symptoms).





                                                                                                     Causes -
The bacterial strains that cause UTIs include:
Escherichia (E.) coli is responsible for most uncomplicated cystitis cases in women, especially in younger women. E. coli is generally a harmless microorganism originating in the intestines. If it spreads to the vaginal opening, it may invade and colonize the bladder, causing an infection. The spread of E. coli to the vaginal opening most commonly occurs when women or girls wipe themselves from back to front after urinating, or after sexual activity.
Staphylococcus saprophyticus accounts for 5 - 15% of UTIs, mostly in younger women.
Klebsiella, Enterococci, and Proteus mirabilis account for most of remaining bacterial organisms that cause UTIs. They are generally found in UTIs in older women.
Rare bacterial causes of UTIs include Ureaplasma urealyticum and Mycoplasma hominis, which are typically harmless organisms."
            android:layout_width="match_parent"
            android:layout_height="wrap_content"
            android:id="@+id/textView4"
            android:textSize="14sp"
            android:textAlignment="center"
            android:textStyle="bold|italic"
            android:background="@android:color/white"
            android:textColor="@android:color/black" />

        <TextView
            android:text="




Symptoms of urinary tract infections may include:
Strong urge to urinate frequently, even immediately after the bladder is emptied
Painful burning sensation when urinating
Discomfort, pressure, or bloating in the lower abdomen
Pain in the pelvic area or back
Cloudy or bloody urine, which may have a strong smell
A urine test can determine if these symptoms are caused by a bacterial infection. Antibiotics are used to treat UTIs. Older people may have a urinary tract infection but have few or no symptoms.






                                                                                                     In order to spread the awareness of UTI related symptoms and to report Antibiotic drug resistance against E.coli, Android based Application was developed for Doctors and patients both. For Patients, Tree based algorithm prediction was done."
            android:layout_width="match_parent"
            android:layout_height="wrap_content"
            android:id="@+id/textView8"
            android:layout_below="@+id/textView4"
            android:textStyle="bold|italic"
            android:textSize="14sp"
            android:textAlignment="center"
            android:layout_alignParentLeft="true"
            android:layout_alignParentStart="true"
            android:background="@android:color/white"
            android:textColor="@android:color/black" />


    </RelativeLayout>
</ScrollView>
